freetaxusa.com 2019-01-19

# FreeTaxUSA® Privacy Policy Regarding Free Tax Preparation and E-file

#### Information Collection and Use

TaxHawk, Inc. is the sole owner of the information collected on www.FreeTaxUSA.com. Information is collected in order for taxpayers to prepare and electronically file their tax returns. Tax return information is only disclosed to appropriate government and financial institutions in order to file tax returns and comply with Internal Revenue Service requirements. The data collected includes everything that is needed to prepare a tax return, such as names, Social Security numbers, birth dates, mailing address, email address, and any tax-related information (e.g. W-2s and 1099 forms). If a purchase is made, credit card information for a credit card payment or bank account information for an e-check payment will be gathered. Information may also be collected from customers who contact us for support. The information collected, such as a phone number, will be used to research and resolve customer questions. As part of an effort to enhance protection of your identity and your personal information, we may match personal information you provide against publicly available information provided by other sources such as a service that provides identity verification.

Due to European Union (EU) and European Economic Area (EEA) regulatory requirements, we do not provide service or intentionally collect data from EU or EEA residents. By using our service, customers represent that they are not EU or EEA residents.

All personally identifiable information gathered during account creation and during the use of the application to prepare taxes is encrypted using secure socket layer technology (SSL).

At times, we may offer a referral service so that you can tell a friend about our products. We will ask you for your friend's name and email address. We will automatically send your friend a one-time email inviting him or her to visit the site. FreeTaxUSA.com stores this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and tracking the success of our referral program. Your friend may contact us at webmaster@FreeTaxUSA.com to request that we remove this information from our database.

#### Data Retention Policy

Active Account Data Retention Policy: An active account is defined as an account that has started a tax return in the last 5 years. Tax return data (including tax return PDF and partial data) will be retained for a maximum of 7 years in active accounts. Data will be deleted on Oct 31st of the 7th year from the original IRS tax due date of the given tax year. For example, if a 2017 tax return is filed before October 31, 2018 the data will be maintained until October 31, 2025 if the account remains active through that period of time. If a return is filed after October 31st of the year it is due, it is considered a prior year return and the same active account policy applies. For example, if a 2015 return, which was due in 2016, exists in a currently active account and is filed in 2020, it will be maintained until October 31, 2023 (7 years after the original IRS tax filing deadline). However, prior year returns will be maintained a minimum of 3 years even if the 7 year retention period has elapsed.

Inactive Account Data Retention Policy: An inactive account is defined as an account that has not started a tax return in the last 5 years. Tax return data (including tax return PDF and partial data) will be retained for a maximum of 5 years in an inactive accounts. Data will be deleted on Oct 31st of the 5th year from the original IRS tax due date of the given tax year. For example, if a 2017 tax return is filed before October 31, 2018 the data will be maintained until October 31, 2023 if the account is inactive through that period of time. If a return is filed after October 31st of the year it is due, it is considered a prior year return. If the account is inactive after filing a prior year return the inactive account policy applies. For example in an inactive account, if a 2014 return with an original due date in 2015 is filed in 2016 it will be maintained until October 31, 2020 (5 years after the original IRS tax filing deadline). However, prior year returns will be maintained a minimum of 3 years even if the 5 year retention period has elapsed.

#### Tracking Technologies / Cookies

Technologies such as cookies or similar technology are used by FreeTaxUSA.com and our marketing, affiliate, service, and analytics partners. These technologies are used in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users' movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

We use cookies to maintain your session while you are signed in to your account, track affiliate referrals, collect analytical data about usage on our site, and to track the effectiveness of our emails. Users can control the use of cookies at the individual browser level. If you reject cookies, you may still use our site, but your ability to use some features or areas of our site may be limited.

We partner with a third party to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests. If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads. You will continue to receive generic ads.

Third parties with whom we partner to provide certain features on our website or to display advertising based upon your web browsing activity also use HTML5 to collect and store information. Various browsers may offer their own management tools for removing HTML5.

#### Usage Information

Like most websites, FreeTaxUSA.com uses log files and analytical software to track website usage. The information collected may include IP addresses, browser types, browser configuration, internet service providers (ISP), referring/exit pages, platform types, and number of clicks to analyze trends, administer the site, track user movement, and gather broad demographic information for use in improving the site. We link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

#### Contests and Giveaways

Contests and giveaways have their own terms and conditions and should be referenced before entering.

#### Communications from FreeTaxUSA.com

Your contact information (email address) may be used to keep you updated on the status of your return, remind you of important dates on the tax calendar, resolve any problems with transmission of your tax return, and provide a confirmation of credit card or direct-debit payments. If you e-file your tax return, an email will be sent to you stating whether the IRS has accepted or rejected your e-filed tax return. If problems occur with the transmission of your tax return, a customer support email may be sent out to explain the problem. FreeTaxUSA.com also sends a confirmation email to serve as a receipt when a taxpayer uses a credit card or checking/savings account to pay for the FreeTaxUSA.com fee.

FreeTaxUSA.com will not use your information to market any third party product or service. Occasionally, FreeTaxUSA.com will send out tax information or promotional material dealing with our products. These are considered optional communications and you as the recipient can specify whether or not you wish to receive this type of communication. This can be done while creating your account, by using the Edit User Profile portion of the application after signing in, by clicking on the "Update Email Preferences" link in the footer of every optional email or by following the instructions found at the following link: https://www.FreeTaxUSA.com/subscriptions.jsp.

#### Service Announcements

On rare occasions, it is necessary to send out a strictly service related announcement. For instance, if service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, FreeTaxUSA.com might send users a notification via email.

#### Customer Service

Customer support for FreeTaxUSA.com is provided through our tax application, email, or phone. When a customer support request is received, we will reply via the customer support portion of the application, email, or phone. If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire to use our service, you may correct, update or delete it by signing in to your account and make any changes. If you have any questions regarding this process you may contact us at [support@FreeTaxUSA.com](mailto:support@FreeTaxUSA.com); we will respond within a reasonable timeframe. Upon request and verification of your identity, FreeTaxUSA.com will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. However, once the IRS accepts your e-filed tax return, no changes can be made to your account that would change any of the information on the tax return.

We will retain your information for as long as needed to provide you services. We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

#### Legal Disclosures

Though every effort is made to preserve user privacy, in certain situations, FreeTaxUSA.com may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We may also disclose your personally identifiable information when required by law wherein we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, to investigate fraud to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order, respond to a government request, bankruptcy proceedings or similar legal process served on our website.

#### Information Sharing

We will share your personally identifiable information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy statement. We do not sell your personally identifiable information to third parties.

#### Service Provider

We may provide your personally identifiable information to companies that provide services to help us with our business activities such as shipping your order. These companies are authorized to use your personally identifiable information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

Customer reviews are collected and managed using a third party service. Any information collected during the review is stored and managed on a third party site. The review and some details provided can be shown publicly.

Account recovery through text messaging is provided through a third party service. A customer's cell phone number will be forwarded to the service in order to send the account recovery message.

#### Credit Card Processing

If during the use of our application you order a product that requires payment, your credit card or direct-debit payment will be processed by a payment processing company. The payment processing companies that we use do not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. No credit card information will be collected unless there is a payment due. Your credit card data is only used to process your payment.

#### Business Transitions

In the event FreeTaxUSA.com goes through a business transition, such as a merger, being acquired by another company, or selling a portion of its assets, the personally identifiable information of users will, in most instances, be part of the assets transferred. Users will be notified, via email and/or through a prominent notice on the FreeTaxUSA.com website, 30 days prior to a change of ownership or control of their personally identifiable information. If as a result of the business transition, the personally identifiable information will be used in a manner different from that stated at the time of collection, users will be given a choice consistent with our notification of changes section.

#### Security

FreeTaxUSA.com maintains physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards that comply with applicable law and federal standards. When users submit sensitive information via the website, it is protected both online and offline. FreeTaxUSA.com uses Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption technology to protect all sensitive information. SSL technology is the most commonly-used method on the Internet to safely transmit data. Access to your personally identifiable information is protected by a password, of your choosing, in order to maintain security for your account. Only you, or someone with whom you share your password, can access your account to make changes to your return or account information.

Along with using SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also take great care to protect user information offline. The FreeTaxUSA.com servers are located in a secure data storage facility with strict security measures and procedures in place. All user information, not just the sensitive information mentioned above, is restricted to only key employees who need the information to perform a specific job function (Example: the customer service manager). Furthermore, all employees are kept up-to-date on the security and privacy practices of FreeTaxUSA.com. Before every tax season, as well as any time new policies are added, employees of FreeTaxUSA.com are notified and/or reminded about the importance placed on privacy, and what they can do to ensure the security of user information. However, no method of transmission over the Internet, or method of electronic storage, is 100% secure. If you have any further questions about the security at FreeTaxUSA.com, you can send an email to [support@FreeTaxUSA.com](mailto:support@FreeTaxUSA.com).

#### Links to 3rd Party Sites

Our Site includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of FreeTaxUSA.com. If you submit personally identifiable information to any of those sites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any website you visit.

#### Social Media Widgets

Our website includes social media widgets, such as the Facebook "Like" button, the "Google+" button, and other social widgets. These features may collect your IP address, the URL of the page you are coming from, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy statement of the company providing it.

#### Notification of Changes

If we decide to change our privacy statement, we will post those changes to this privacy statement, the homepage, and there may be other places we deem appropriate so that you are aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. We reserve the right to modify this privacy statement at any time, so please review it frequently. If we make material changes to this statement, we will notify you here, by email, or by means of a notice on our homepage prior to the change becoming effective.

#### Contact Information

If you have additional questions regarding FreeTaxUSA.com's privacy or security policies, please send your question to [support@FreeTaxUSA.com](mailto:support@FreeTaxUSA.com).

Or, address your written question to:

          **FreeTaxUSA - Privacy**   
         1366 East 1120 South   
         Provo, UT  84606

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.
